Resume 2022-11-11, 9:55 AM

TOFIK MOHAMMED

EMAIL: tofik.a.moh1999@gmail.com **WEBSITE:** http://tofweb.services **PHONE:** 6473541889 **LOCATION:** Toronto, ON **GITHUB:** https://github.com/tofi-124

SUMMARY

I am a professional Web developer, mastering various platforms and experience with different language such as HTML and Javascript; and CSS and frameworks like React, Node as well as experience in SQL and PSQL. Also dedicated programmer with a curious mind and strong problem-solving abilities with proven collaboration, communication, and interpersonal skills.

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs, Diploma in Full-Stack Web Development 2021 - 2022

BSC Computer Security York University (Partial Completion) 2020 - 2021

NPower Digital Customer Care 2019 - 2019

EMPLOYMENT

Bell, Software Developer, Ontario

July 2022 - Current

- Upgraded, configured and debugged existing systems that used C#, VB .NET framewroks.
- Designed and implemented highly scalable ELK (ElasticSearch, Logstash, and Kibana) stack and ElastiCache solutions to monitor the RAN network and data-flows that ingest and aggregate from our cell towers.
- Implemented Zabbix monitoring for diverse components, including networks, servers, virtual machines (VMs) and cloud services that we use to do our daily data aggregations.
- Used Shell scripts to day to day activities and tasks for automating.
- Experienced with through hands-on experience in all Hadoop, impala and SQL.

Halycon IQ, Web Application Developer, Toronto, ON

Mar. 2022 - Apr. 2022

- Led development of an e-commerce website for client, including websitedesign and selecting a hosting company.
- Created contact page and checkout page, and worked within a team of 5 todevelop front-end layout and confirm database hosting.
- Website can be viewed here: riipen-project.vercel.app

CIBC, Fraud and Dispute Specialist

June 2019 - May 2020

- Took full responsibility for client calls, responding to them in a warm, courteous, and professional manner and ensuring prompt resolution of identified concerns while managing risk and offering an amazing client experience.
- Created dispute cases and fraud reports for CIBC Visa and Mastercard cardholders in order to initiate charge-backs.
- Used my in-depth fraud knowledge and problem-solving skills to identify and act on potential fraud transactions.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, Java, C++

LIBRARIES/FRAMEWORK: REACT, RUBY, NODE EXPRESS, AJAX, PSQL, Next Js, Jquery, Commerce JS

PROJECTS

Scheduler

Students can connect with mentors in real-time through this React-based web app and schedule meetings.

Tech Stack: Axios, React, Cypress, Classnames, React-dom, Normalize.css

Tweeter Project

Tweeter is a simple, single-page web clone of twitter built using AJAX.

Tech Stack: Express, jQuery, Node

Resource Wall Project

Resource-Wall is a full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to save resources, as well as register and login. Any user can rate or comment on a resource, and other users can see the average rating as well as other users' comments.

Tech Stack: Express, Node.JS

AWARDS

Excel Rate Award, Cibc

2020

The Excelerate quarterly award is given to those that have maintained a balanced performance for the duration of the quarter.

https://resume.creddle.io/

Resume 2022-11-11, 9:55 AM

https://resume.creddle.io/